(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Over the clouds
作詞：山本成美 作曲：池上浩一
Lyrics: Narumi Yamamoto / Composition: Koichi Ikegami
悲しみに濡れた月が静かに
The moon, wet with sadness, quietly
大地を赤く染めて消える
dyes the earth red and disappears
僕の声が聞こえますか
Can you hear my voice?
殺伐としたこの時代で
In this bloodthirsty era
僕は僕でいられますか
can I still be myself?
心溢れだす涙は
The tears that overflow from my heart
きっと未来を求めてる証なの
must be proof that I'm seeking the future
今の無理と嘆かないで 前を見つめて
Don't lament that it's impossible now, look ahead
You can get over over the clouds
季節を移ろう風のざわめき
The rustling of the wind as the seasons change
終わりの見えない戦いへの序曲
An overture to a never-ending battle
人はなぜに忘れてくの
Why do people keep on forgetting?
ありきたりのこの日常に
In this ordinary daily life
かけがえのないものがあると
that there are irreplaceable things
ボロボロになった羽でも
Even with tattered wings
誰が想うその気持ちがあるなら
if you have those feelings that someone cares
どんな苦しみに向かっても飛んでいけるさ
no matter what suffering you face, you can fly
You can get over over the clouds
Over the clouds
僕の声が聞こえますか
Can you hear my voice?
殺伐としたこの時代で
In this bloodthirsty era
僕は僕でいられますか
Can I still be myself?
心あふれだす涙は
The tears overflowing from my heart
きっと未来を求めてる証なの
Are surely proof that I'm seeking the future
ボロボロになった羽でも
Even with tattered wings
誰かを想うその気持ちがあるなら
If there's a feeling of thinking about someone
どんな苦しみに向かっても飛んでいけるさ
No matter what suffering I face, I can fly
You can get over over the clouds
闇に灯るは命の光
What lights up the darkness is the light of life
ぱあー！
Paa!
ということで皆さん、ただいまー！
So everyone, I'm back!
ホロライブ5期生、獅白ぼたんです。
I'm Shishiro Botan from Hololive Gen 5.
今日はですね、5期生が、2周年！
Today, Gen 5 is at its 2nd anniversary!
2!
2周年というところで、噛んでません。
It's my 2nd anniversary, and I didn't stumble.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
まだまだちょっとホロライブに入ってぺーぺーの私達ですがね
We're still newbies who just joined Hololive, but...
見守っていただければ嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you could watch over us.
ということで今日は2周年ライブにさせていただきました。
So today, I'm holding a 2nd anniversary live.
ちょっとステージね、見てほしい。
I want you to take a look at the stage.
ロゴ！
The logo!
ちゃんとね、作ってもらって、
It was made specifically for this,
後ろにね、SSRBの…こっちも行こうか。
and in the back, the SSRB... Let's go this way too.
こっち。ほら見て！
This way. Look!
ネオンがすごい光ってるよ。
The neon lights are shining so brightly.
これね、ちょっとね歌ってる時とかね、
These, when I'm singing and all,
結構ビカビカ光ってね、一緒に演出してくれるようになってるんで、
they flash quite a bit and help with the performance,
まあ今日はこういうね、SSRBも一緒にお祝いに駆けつけてくれましたということで、
so today, the SSRBs have also rushed here to celebrate together,
見ていただければ嬉しいなと思ってます。
so I'd be happy if you could watch them.
おお、すごい！
Wow, amazing!
おー、広い！
Oh, it's so wide!
すごいね。
It's incredible.
いや、去年、えっとね、
Well, last year, let's see,
私、まあ、前からちょっと言ってたんですけど、
I've mentioned this before, but...
あんまりやっぱりその入った当初、歌が上手くなく…
when I first joined, I wasn't very good at singing...
へにゃへにゃ歌だったんですけど、
My singing was quite weak,
まあ、2年も経てばね、多少はちょっとは歌えるようになったのかな。
but after two years, I think I can sing a bit better now.
まあいろいろ練習したりとか、みんなと一緒に歌わせてもらったりとかして、
Through various practices and singing with everyone,
まあ、多少3分の1ぐらい腹から声は出るようになったので、
I can finally project my voice from my core a little bit more,
今日はそのね、成果をね、見せられたらいいかなと思っております。
so I hope I can show the results today.
じゃあ、この後はね、
Well then, after this,
たくさんゲストの方もね、
many guests have also,
ありがたいことに駆けつけてくれましたので、
thankfully, rushed here to join,
楽しんでいただけると嬉しいなと思っておりますんで。
so I hope you'll enjoy it.
はい、最後までよかったら見ていってください。
Yes, please watch until the end if you'd like.
ありがとね。
Thank you.
じゃあ、次の曲、行ってみましょうか。
Now, shall we move on to the next song?
じゃあ、次はなんだろうな？
Well, what's next?
気になる？
Are you curious?
じゃあ、ちょっと次の曲、行ってみましょう。
Then, let's move on to the next song.
ふっ！
Fu!
irony
そんな優しくしないで
Don't be so kind to me
どんな顔すればいいの?
What kind of face should I make?
積み重ねた言葉で見えないよ
I can't see through the accumulated words
君の横顔
Your side profile
どこだっけ 隠した鍵は見つからないままで
Where was it? The hidden key remains unfound
ため息 すれ違いに意地張って疲れてちゃう
Sighing, getting tired of being stubborn over misunderstandings
ほんの少し遠く手は届かない
Just a little bit too far for my hand to reach
ちゃんと掴みたいのかな 君のその影
Do I really want to grab it? Your shadow
そんな優しくしないで
Don't be so kind to me
ほらまた傷つけあって
Look, we're hurting each other again
積み重ねたウソで動けなくなってる
I'm unable to move due to the accumulated lies
そんな眼で見つめないで
Don't look at me with those eyes
どんな顔すればいいの?
What kind of face should I make?
迷ってばっかだ
I'm just lost
...だけど いつかは 笑えるのかな
...but I wonder if I'll be able to smile someday.
屈託のない日々を 君と過ごしてきたんだろう
I suppose I've spent carefree days with you.
それでも 交わした言葉は 少なすぎるね
Even so, the words we've exchanged are far too few.
ほんの少し近く 君との距離が
I can't quite grasp the distance between us,
うまく掴めないんだ あとちょっとなのに
even though it's just a little bit closer.
そんな優しくしないで ほらまた傷つけあって
Don't be so kind to me; look, we're hurting each other again.
積み重ねたウソで 聞こえないよ 君の言葉
I can't hear your words through all the lies we've piled up.
本当の声を隠して 口ずさむ このメロディ
Hiding my true voice, I hum this melody.
ゆっくりと 変わってく心に 身をまかせて
I'll just surrender myself to my slowly changing heart.
自分のことなんて わからないし
I don't even understand myself.
君のこと 知りたい気もするけど
Although I feel like I want to know about you.
ぶつかる気持ちを 少し抑えて
Restraining my clashing feelings,
見えない壁 手探りで探すよ
I'll grope for that invisible wall.
そんな優しくしないで ほらまた傷つけあって
Don't be so kind to me; look, we're hurting each other again.
積み重ねたウソは もうツラいだけだからね
The lies we've piled up are just painful now.
すぐに会いに行きたいけど 言葉は見つからないし
I want to go see you right away, but I can't find the words.
最後の1ページは 君には笑顔見せたい
For the last page, I want to show you a smile.
イエーイ！ ぼたん先輩、2周年おめでとうございます！
Yay! Botan-senpai, happy 2nd anniversary!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
今日ね、我々ね、
Today, we...
水着！
Swimsuits!
かわいい！
So cute!
ちょっと、向いて、向いて。
Look this way, this way.
なんか違う！ 思ってたんと違う！
Something's different! This isn't what I expected!
思ってたんとちゃう。なんかおかしいでしょ。
It's not what I expected. Something is weird.
ほら私セクシーでしょ？
See, I'm sexy, right?
せっかくなんで、みんなでスクショとか撮れたら
Since we're here, let's take some screenshots
いいかなって感じで。
and get that summer vibe.
夏っぽいポーズをちょっと。
Let's do a summer-like pose.
夏っぽいポーズなんかある？
Any ideas for a summer pose?
ここ今二人で完結した。
The two of them just finished their own thing.
水しぶきだ、水しぶき。
A water splash! A water splash!
水しぶき？ どんなの？
A water splash? Like what?
キャッキャッ、なんか違うな。
Splish! Splash! ...Something's wrong.
オラオラオラ！
Ora ora ora!
なんか違うよ。
Something's wrong.
ちょっと時間も押してるからね。
We're running a bit behind schedule.
押してるんだｗ
Running behind? lol
わためちょっと背低いから前前。
Watame, you're a bit short, so come to the front.
え、いいの？
Oh, is it okay?
ぼたんちょっと美味しそうな匂いがする。
Botan, you smell delicious.
なんか違う。美味しそうな匂いする。
Something's wrong. Smells delicious?
なんか違うくない？
Isn't something wrong?
あ、なんかいい。
Oh, this is nice.
いいですね。スクショみんな撮れた？
This is great. Did everyone get their screenshots?
撮れた？
Did you get them?
ぷるぷるぷるぷる。
Wiggle wiggle wiggle...
じゃあね、ちょっとごめんね。
Sorry, but we have many guests
今日はたくさんのゲストが来るから。
coming today.
時間がね。
So we're out of time.
それはしょうがないですね。
That's too bad.
ちょっと押しちゃうんだ。
We're running over.
まっすぐ行きましょう、もう。わため先輩。
Let's keep moving. Watame-senpai.
まだここにいる！
I'm still here!
あ、ダメでしょ、それは。
Hey, you can't do that.
ここにいるんだー！
I want to stay here!
帰りますよ。
We're leaving.
ああ...
Oh...
こうなったらね、うちらで食べちゃいましょう。
Since it's come to this, let's just eat her.
え、食べられたいってことだな。
Wait, that means I'm going to be eaten.
いやそういうことじゃない。いい匂いするね、君。
No, that's not it. You smell good.
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける ENJOY 届けたい胸の鼓動
ENJOY the music keeps playing, ENJOY the heartbeat I want to deliver
ココロオドル アンコール沸かす Dance Dance Dance Ready Go!
My heart is dancing, stirring up an encore, Dance Dance Dance Ready Go!
今宵は宵より飛び越し踊り乗りお泳ぎ続け
Tonight, jumping beyond the dusk, dancing, riding, keep swimming
ENJOY ENJOY ENJOY 鼓舞する心響き続け
ENJOY ENJOY ENJOY the heart that inspires keeps echoing
ノリノリでノリノリな言葉が出てきた ここはココロオドルところだから
Lively words came out in high spirits, because this is the place where the heart dances
置いてかないよ 追い付きたいなら GET UP STAND UP いくしかねぇ
I won't leave you behind, if you want to catch up, GET UP STAND UP, you just gotta go
ゆくしかねぇ やっぱ気付いたんだ 100% 幸せのいっちょあがり 鳴らせ CLAP CLAP
Gotta go, I realized after all, 100% happiness is ready, make it ring, CLAP CLAP
仲間同士を 同士 詰め込んで アッパーなテンションのシチュエーション
Stuffing fellow comrades together, an upper-tension situation
GLEAMING CLEANING この場の空気 ツール 作る サークル 繋がる ブギー
GLEAMING CLEANING, the air here, tool making circle connected boogie
リフレッシュ 気晴らし ここらのみんな その価値あるから SWING SWING
Refresh, recreation, everyone here, because it's worth it, SWING SWING
恥じ恥じかしがっていても出来る IMAGINATION 望むところだ 茶の間とこの間
Even if you're feeling shy, you can do it, IMAGINATION, just what I want, between the tea room and the space between
所構わず ボタン一つで踊る心が
No matter where you are, with just one button, the dancing heart is...
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける ENJOY 届けたい胸の鼓動
ENJOY the music keeps playing, ENJOY the heartbeat I want to deliver
ココロオドル アンコール沸かす Dance Dance Dance Ready Go!
My heart is dancing, stirring up an encore, Dance Dance Dance Ready Go!
今宵は宵より飛び越し踊り乗りお泳ぎ続け
Tonight, jumping beyond the dusk, dancing, riding, keep swimming
ENJOY ENJOY ENJOY 鼓舞する心響き続け
ENJOY ENJOY ENJOY the heart that inspires keeps echoing
あっぱれなハリきり 俺は急いで 歯磨く手間も取らせんさ皆
Brilliant enthusiasm, I'm in a hurry, won't even let everyone have time to brush their teeth
編み出すつーか勝手 ここら騒ぎ出す 時間場所など関係ないぜ
Creating, or rather, freely, this area starts to get noisy, time and place don't matter
探せばバッチリ日常メリハリ 毎日変わる音フレッシュデリバリー
If you look, you'll find it perfectly, daily modulation, fresh delivery of sounds changing every day
揺らす 揺らす パーティーの奥増す増す ベストなる向かう方向先はフレッシュ
Swaying, swaying, increasing the depth of the party more and more, the direction to aim for is fresh
どうだそこがどうかな ところどころ心躍る幸福幸せだから今日は今日
How's that? How about it? Here and there, the heart dances with happiness, so today is today
振り切る昨日 心から躍らすこのひととき
Shaking off yesterday, making this moment dance from the heart
そっとドア開けたらフロア 浮き足立つ抜け出す揺れるコア
When you softly open the door, the floor... restless, breaking out, the core is swaying
UP AND DOWN こちとらタフでタフ COME ON 加速かまわん COME ON
UP AND DOWN, we're tough and tough, COME ON, acceleration doesn't matter, COME ON
待っていてもいらない 心だけじゃおさまんない じっとしてられない
Even if you wait, you don't need it, just the heart isn't enough, can't stay still
SHAKE YOUR BODY ぎこちないなら鳴らして可愛い クラップクラップ弾むマネー
SHAKE YOUR BODY, if you're awkward, make it sound, cute clap clap, bouncing money
L-L-L-LIVE LIFE ぶっ飛びアライブ 笑い愛し合える喜怒哀楽
L-L-L-LIVE LIFE, jumping alive, the joy, anger, grief and humor we can love each other with
刻む音と言葉繋ぐこの場 届いてるなら MAKE SOME NOISE
Tying the rhythm and words together here, if it's reaching you, MAKE SOME NOISE
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける ENJOY 届けたい胸の鼓動
ENJOY the music keeps playing, ENJOY the heartbeat I want to deliver
ココロオドル アンコール沸かす Dance Dance Dance Ready Go!
My heart is dancing, stirring up an encore, Dance Dance Dance Ready Go!
今宵は宵より飛び越し踊り乗りお泳ぎ続け
Tonight, jumping beyond the dusk, dancing, riding, keep swimming
ENJOY ENJOY ENJOY 鼓舞する心響き続け
ENJOY ENJOY ENJOY the heart that inspires keeps echoing
グレイトフル描くスケールはでかく 楽しむもんだエラステック
The scale I draw gratefully is huge, it's something to enjoy, elastic
狙う暇なんか単純に簡単 預けてカウントダウン 3-2-1
No time to aim, simply easy, leave it to the countdown 3-2-1
なりふり構わず夢中で駆け抜けろ ITS MY TIME ITS MY GAME
Disregarding appearances, run through in a trance, IT'S MY TIME IT'S MY GAME
さらに深い感動へ 猛烈 OH YEAH! ココロオドル今日へ
Towards even deeper emotion, intense OH YEAH! To the heart-dancing today
今宵は宵より飛び越し踊り乗りお泳ぎ続け
Tonight, jumping beyond the dusk, dancing, riding, keep swimming
ENJOY 音楽は鳴り続ける ENJOY 届けたい胸の鼓動
ENJOY the music keeps playing, ENJOY the heartbeat I want to deliver
ココロオドル アンコール沸かす Dance Dance Dance Ready Go!
My heart is dancing, stirring up an encore, Dance Dance Dance Ready Go!
今宵は宵より飛び越し踊り乗りお泳ぎ続け
Tonight, jumping beyond the dusk, dancing, riding, keep swimming
ENJOY ENJOY ENJOY 鼓舞する心響き続け
ENJOY ENJOY ENJOY the heart that inspires keeps echoing
ENJOY ENJOY ENJOY ENJOY
ココロオドル アンコール沸かす Dance Dance Dance Ready Go!
My heart is dancing, stirring up an encore, Dance Dance Dance Ready Go!
今宵は宵より飛び越し踊り乗りお泳ぎ続け
Tonight, jumping beyond the dusk, dancing, riding, keep swimming
ENJOY ENJOY ENJOY 鼓舞する心響き続け
ENJOY ENJOY ENJOY the heart that inspires keeps echoing
いえーい！ぼたんおめでとうー！
Yay! Congrats Botan!
ぼたんおめでとうー！
Congrats Botan!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
このままじゃなんかラップ抗争になるからサングラス取るぜ
If we keep going it'll turn into a rap battle, so I'm taking the sunglasses off
イエーイ！
Yay!
ありがとうございます！おめでとう、ぼたん！
Thank you very much! Congrats, Botan!
2周年になりました。まだ2年だね。
It's my 2nd anniversary. It's only been two years.
2年ですって。ベビーだね、まだね。
They say two years. Still a baby, isn't it?
これからやな。まだ元気だろ。大丈夫！
It's from here on. We're still energetic. No problem!
あとね今日はみんなで水着を着れたので、ちょっとねスクショタイムをしたいなと。
And since we all got to wear swimsuits today, I want to have a bit of a screenshot time.
おー！
Whoa!
どうするどうする？
What should we do?
夏っぽいポーズ。
Summer-like poses.
夏っぽいポーズ？
Summer-like poses?
え、夏、こういうの？ビーチバレーみたいな。
Eh, summer... like this? Like beach volleyball.
あ、ビーチバレー！
Ah, beach volleyball!
ほら、撮れ！撮れるもんなら撮ってみろ！
Look, take a picture! Take it if you can!
取れたかな？無理か。無理だろうな。
Did you get it? Maybe not. It's probably impossible.
無理だな。大丈夫かな？
Impossible, right. I wonder if they're okay?
あと、ちょっと３人で、ちょっと固まってなんか撮りたいな。
And I want to take a shot of the three of us all huddled up.
撮りたい！
Let's do it!
お、お、可愛い！
Oh, oh, cute!
イェーイ！
Yay!
じゃあね、せっかくね、ちょっと３人、ちょっと我々尻尾があるので、
Well then, since the three of us all have tails,
お、尻尾！
Oh, tails!
尻尾。
Tails.
撮って撮って！
Take a photo, take a photo!
撮って！
Take it!
ちょっと、次の現場があるので。
I have another scene to get to.
次の現場！
Another scene!
行ってくるぜ！
I'm off!
よーよーよーよー！おめでとう！ありがとう！
Yo yo yo yo! Congratulations! Thank you!
忘れじの言の葉
作詞 砂守岳央 作曲 松岡美弥子
Forgotten Words
Lyrics: Takeo Sunamori / Music: Miyako Matsuoka
言の葉を紡いで
Spinning the words
まどろんだ泡沫
Drowsy bubbles
旅人 迷い込む
A traveler wanders in
御伽の深い霧
Into the deep mist of folklore
差し伸べた手のひら
The palm of an outstretched hand
そっと触れる予感
A premonition of a soft touch
受け止めてこぼれた
Caught and overflowed
光のひとしずく
A single drop of light
面影 移ろって
The vestige shifts
微笑んだ幻
A smiling phantom
想いの果てる場所
The place where feelings end
まだ遥か遠くて
Is still far, far away
求め探して彷徨って
Seeking, searching, and wandering
やがて歌われて
Eventually being sung
幾千 幾万 幾億の旋律となる
Becoming a melody of thousands, millions, billions
いつか失い奪われて
Even if one day it's lost and stolen
消える定めでも
Even if it's destined to vanish
それは忘れられることなき物語
It is a story that will never be forgotten
指先を絡めて
Entwining fingertips
触れる誰かの夢
Touching someone's dream
刻まれた想いの
Only the echoes of
木霊だけが響く
Carved feelings resound
言の葉を紡いで
Spinning the words
まどろんだ泡沫
Drowsy bubbles
旅人の名前を
The name of the traveler
御伽噺という
Is called a fairy tale
求め探して彷徨って
Seeking, searching, and wandering
やがて道となり
Eventually becoming a path
幾千 幾万 幾億の英雄は行く
Thousands, millions, billions of heroes go on
いつか失い奪われて
Even if one day it's lost and stolen
消える定めでも
Even if it's destined to vanish
それは忘れられることなくここにある
It is right here, never to be forgotten
求め探して彷徨って
Seeking, searching, and wandering
やがて歌われて
Eventually being sung
幾千 幾万 幾億の旋律となる
Becoming a melody of thousands, millions, billions
いつか失い奪われて
Even if one day it's lost and stolen
消える定めでも
Even if it's destined to vanish
それは忘れられることなき物語
It is a story that will never be forgotten
Sign
獅白ぼたん / 癒月ちょこ / 大空スバル / 姫森ルーナ
Shishiro Botan / Yuzuki Choco / Oozora Subaru / Himemori Luna
今見上げてる
I'm looking up now
輝きたちは
at these shining lights
何度も遥か
They've traveled from afar
旅をしてきた
countless times
暗闇を越え
Crossing through the darkness
辿り着いたんだ
they finally arrived here
届けたいメッセージ
The messages they want to deliver
一つずつ握りしめて
clutched tightly one by one
君と出会ったから
Because I met you
一つの光になる
we become a single light
あの星と星は遠く
Those stars are so far apart
離れて呼び合っていた
yet they were calling to each other
それぞれが違った色のままで
Each remaining in their own different colors
宇宙に大きなサインを描いて
Drawing a grand sign across the universe
自分の選んだ未来と
If the future I've chosen
誰かの望んだ未来が
and the future someone else wished for
繋がっていること信じたなら
are believed to be connected
きっとその笑顔放つ光
then surely the light your smile radiates...
同じ彼方の
From the same distance
見果てぬ夢を
endless dreams
幾千の中から
from among thousands
見つけられるよ
can be found
諦めない勇気
The courage to never give up
その眩しさが
that brightness
ここにいるんだって
reminds me that I am here
気づかせてくれたときに
when it made me realize
君の眼差しが
If your gaze
まっすぐに見ているなら
is looking straight ahead
そう星と星のように
Yes, just like stars
誰もが呼び合えるんだ
everyone can call to each other
それぞれに希望の色を持って
Each holding a color of hope
明日という名のサインを描いて
Drawing a sign called tomorrow
自分の選んだ誓いと
If the vow I've chosen
誰かを想う願いが
and the wish thinking of someone
重なっていること感じるのは
are felt to be overlapping
きっとその笑顔映す光
then surely the light your smile reflects...
その手が
Those hands
その目が
Those eyes
辿った軌跡だけが
Only the traces they followed
新しい星座を作って
create a new constellation
物語をまた繋いでゆく
and continue to connect the story
そう星と星は遠く
Yes, those stars are so far apart
離れて呼び合ってるんだ
calling to each other from a distance
それぞれが違った色のままで
Each remaining in their own different colors
宇宙に大きなサインを描く
Drawing a grand sign across the universe
自分の選んだ未来と
Because I believed the future I've chosen
誰かの望んだ未来が
and the future someone else wished for
輝いていけると信じたから
can go on shining together
きっと君なら届く遥か遠く
Surely you can reach far, far away
放つ光
The light you radiate
ぼたんちゃん
Botan-chan!
2周年おめでとうだよい！
Happy 2nd Anniversary!
ありがとうだよい！
Thank you!
せーの
One, two...
らららいおん、らららいおん、らららいおん
La-la-lion, la-la-lion, la-la-lion!
大丈夫これ？
Is this okay?
大丈夫？
Are we good?
らららいおん... 大分大丈夫だよい！
La-la-lion... It's mostly okay!
ありがとうだよい！
Thank you!
花のいろが 変われるほどの
Enough for the color of flowers to change
長い時の 密度に近くて
Close to the density of a long time
フレームは一瞬 スローモーション
A frame is an instant, in slow motion
一直線 光 咲くように
Like a straight line of light blooming
空気を揺らせ 鼓動を鳴らせ
Shake the air, make your heartbeat ring
静かな夜に 今火をつけるの
Now set fire to the quiet night
恋とも全然 違うエモーション
An emotion completely different from love
本当に それだけなの
Really, that's all it is
それだけなの
That's all it is
火花のように FLASH 光る 最高ライティングで
Like a spark, FLASH, shining with the best lighting
鳴らした音も 置き去りにして
Leaving even the sound you made behind
FLASH 込める 最高ライティングスピード
FLASH, putting in the best lighting speed
速い時の中で ちはやふる
In the fast flow of time, Chihayafuru
FLASH 光る 最高ライティングで
FLASH, shining with the best lighting
かざした手を 弓矢にかえて
Turning your raised hand into a bow and arrow
FLASH 込める 最高ライティングスピード
FLASH, putting in the best lighting speed
笑顔シンクロのままで 届け 空へ FLASH
With our smiles in sync, reach the sky, FLASH
舞いおちる火花が 地につくまでの
Until the dancing sparks reach the ground
刹那的な 速度に近くて
Close to an ephemeral speed
フレームは一瞬 ハイスピードで
A frame is an instant, at high speed
一直線 光 咲くように
Like a straight line of light blooming
空気を揺らせ 鼓動を鳴らせ
Shake the air, make your heartbeat ring
静かな夜に 今火をつけるの
Now set fire to the quiet night
恋とも全然 違うエモーション
An emotion completely different from love
今夜は これからなの
Tonight is just beginning
火花のように FLASH 光る 最高ライティングで
Like a spark, FLASH, shining with the best lighting
鳴らした音も 置き去りにして
Leaving even the sound you made behind
FLASH 込める 最高ライティングスピード
FLASH, putting in the best lighting speed
速い時の中で ちはやふる
In the fast flow of time, Chihayafuru
FLASH 光る 最高ライティングで
FLASH, shining with the best lighting
かざした手を 弓矢にかえて
Turning your raised hand into a bow and arrow
FLASH 込める 最高ライティングスピード
FLASH, putting in the best lighting speed
笑顔シンクロのままで 届け 空へ FLASH
With our smiles in sync, reach the sky, FLASH
ちはやふる
Chihayafuru
うぇーい！
Yay!
お疲れ様ー！ありがとう！
Good job! Thank you!
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much! Thank you very much!
なんかね、ぺこら先輩のライブにも出たし、トワ様のライブにも出て…
You know, I appeared in Pekora-senpai's live, and also in Towa-sama's live...
3回目よ。
This is the third time.
いぇーい！
Yay!
なんか7月8月でぺぽっと急に集まったぺこね。
Pippote suddenly gathered a lot in July and August, didn't we?
確かにね。
That's true.
で、次の記念日の人、はい！
And who's the next one having an anniversary? Yes!
はーい！1月3日！
Me! January 3rd!
1月12！
January 12th!
あ、1月だ。
Oh, it's January.
1月だ。
It's January.
えっと…9月なんだけど……あははは！
Well... mine is in September... Ahahaha!
じゃあ9月は…9月はどうかな、再集合できるかな？
Well, for September... I wonder if we can gather again in September?
「良いお年を」って感じ？
Does this feel like a "Have a good year" situation?
良いお年？え、もうそれまで集まんないってこと？
Good year? Wait, does that mean we won't meet until then?
なんか最近ちょっとだってライブばっかぺこっとクラスもの。
Lately, it seems we only gather for lives.
ライブでしか集まんない…
We only meet for lives...
ぺぽっとライブでしか集まらない説。
The theory that Pippote only gathers for lives.
まずいぺこねー。えーでも、まあ…
That's not good. Well, even so...
じゃあ来年も良いお年を、ということで。
Then, let's say "Have a good year" for next year too.
良いお年を！
Have a good year!
まずいぺこよー！
That's bad!
帰るか。帰ろ。せーの！
Shall we go? Let's go. One, two!
おだらよー！
Odarayo!
おだらよー！いいお年をー！
Odarayo! Have a good year!
unlasting
作詞: LiSA 作曲: 草野華余子
Lyrics: LiSA Composition: Kayoko Kusano
独りきりでも平気と
Saying I'm fine even being all alone
きっとこぼれ落ちた
Surely, they overflowed and fell
強がり
Words of false strength
二人の眩しすぎた日が
The days when we two were too bright
こんなに悲しい
Are this sad
独りで生きられるなら
If I can live alone
誰か愛したりしないから
Then I wouldn't love anyone else
貴方の香り
Your scent
貴方の話し方
Your way of speaking
今も身体中に“愛のカケラ”が残ってるよ
Even now, fragments of love remain throughout my body
私の願い
My wish
私の願いはただ…
My wish is just...
どうか貴方もどこかで
Please, you as well, somewhere
泣いていますように
I hope you are crying
いつも新しい一歩は
A new step is always
重くて寂しい
Heavy and lonely
もし生まれ変わっても
Even if I am reborn
もう一度貴方に出会いたい
I want to meet you once more
真夏の日差し
The midsummer sunlight
真冬の白い雪
The white snow of midwinter
巡る季節中に“愛のカケラ”が舞い落ちて
Throughout the turning seasons, fragments of love flutter down
幸せなのにどこかで寂しいのは
The reason I feel lonely somewhere even though I'm happy
貴方よりも大きな
Is because of my love,
私の愛のせい
which is greater than yours
...あなたが持ったまま
...while you still have it
歌う意味をなくしたカナリア
A canary that has lost its meaning for singing
凍りつく　独り　籠の中で
Freezing, alone inside a cage
貴方の香り
Your scent
貴方の話し方
The way you talk
今も身体中に　愛のカケラが残ってるよ
Even now, fragments of love remain throughout my body
私の願いはただ...
My wish is simply...
どうかあなたが幸せでありますように
I hope that you will be happy
空飛ぶ羽根と引き換えに
In exchange for wings to fly through the sky
繋ぎ合う手を選んだ僕ら
We chose to hold each other's hands
それでも空に魅せられて
Even so, we are captivated by the sky
夢を重ねるのは罪か
Is it a sin to pile up our dreams?
夏は秋の背中を見て
Summer looks at the back of Autumn
その顔を思い浮かべる
And envisions that face
憧れなのか　恋なのか
Is it longing, or is it love?
叶わぬと知っていながら
Knowing it will never come true
通り雨が通り雨と
Long before a passing shower...
木漏れ日たちが木漏れ日と
...and the sunbeams filtering through leaves...
名乗るずっとずっとずっと前から
...called themselves by those names
あなたはあなたでいたんだろう
You were probably being you
重力が眠りにつく
When gravity falls asleep
1000年に一度の今日
On this once-in-a-millennium day
太陽の死角に立ち
Standing in the sun's blind spot
僕らこの星を出よう
Let's leave this planet
彼が目覚めた時
When he wakes up
連れ戻せない場所へ
To a place where we can't be brought back
せーので大地を蹴って
Kick off the earth on the count of three
ここではない星へ
Head for a planet that isn't here
行こう
Let's go
夏風に焦る心が
A heart impatient in the summer breeze
夏をさらに早送るよ
Fast-forwards the summer even more
めまぐるしい景色の中
In the dizzying scenery
君だけじゃないと分かって見えた
I saw that it wasn't just you
君と出会ったあの日から
From the day I met you
ぱたりと夜、夢はやんだよ
Suddenly at night, the dreams stopped
土の中で待ち焦がれた
Longed for deep within the earth
叶えるその時は今だ
The time to fulfill it is now
重力が眠りにつく　千年に一度の今日
Gravity falls asleep, a once-in-a-thousand-year today
花火の音に乗せ　僕らこの星を出よう
Riding the sound of fireworks, let's leave this star
彼が目を覚ました時　連れ戻せない場所へ
To a place where they can't bring us back when he wakes up
せーので大地を蹴って　ここではない星へ
One, two, kick off the earth, to a star that isn't here
行こう
Let's go
もう少しで運命の向こう
Just a bit more to the other side of destiny
もう少しで文明の向こう
Just a bit more to the other side of civilization
もう少しで運命の向こう
Just a bit more to the other side of destiny
もう少しで...
Just a bit more...
行こう
Let's go
もう少しで運命の向こう
Just a bit more to the other side of destiny
もう少しで文明の向こう
Just a bit more to the other side of civilization
もう少しで運命の向こう
Just a bit more to the other side of destiny
もう少しで...
Just a bit more...
夢に僕らで帆を張って
Setting sail with our dreams
来たるべき日のために夜を越え
Crossing the night for the day to come
いざ期待だけ満タンで
Now, full of anticipation
あとはどうにかなるさと肩を組んだ
Linked shoulders, saying things will work out somehow
怖くない　わけない　でも止まんない
It's not that I'm not scared, but I won't stop
ピンチの先回りしたって僕らじゃしょうがない
It's no use if we try to anticipate trouble
僕らの恋が言う
Our love says
声が言う
Voice says
行けと言う
Says to go
イェーイ！
Yay!
どんだけイェーイ言うねんな。
How many times are you gonna say "yay"?
ということで、4人でグランドエスケープ歌わせていただきました！
So, the four of us sang Grand Escape!
イェーイ！
Yay!
さっきまであんなにかっこよかったのにもうこんなん。
You were so cool just a moment ago, and now it's like this.
ということでね、はい。
So, yes.
5期生も、2年経ちました！
It's been 2 years since the 5th generation started!
イェーイ！2周年！
Yay! 2nd Anniversary!
2年経ったかっていうそんな感覚はするわ。
I really feel like 2 years have passed.
早い！早い！
So fast! So fast!
まぁ、今後も5期生でね、
Well, I hope we can continue
こうやって色々わちゃわちゃやっていけたら嬉しいなと思ってます。
to mess around together as the 5th generation.
いつも通りに。
Just like always.
イェーイ！
Yay!
じゃあね、じゃあ。
Well then.
次の3年目も、5期生で歌いたいから、ちょっと来てくれよな！
I want to sing as the 5th generation in the 3rd year too, so please come!
いいよ！行こう！
Sure! Let's go!
じゃあ、またシャボンディ諸島で会おう。
Then, let's meet again at Sabaody Archipelago.
お宝見つけに行こうか。
Shall we go find the treasure?
ビブルカードをね。
The Vivre Card, right?
行こう！
Let's go!
出航！
Set sail!
出航はだめ。
No "set sail."
さてさて、配信の途中ですが重大な告知が2つあります。
Now then, in the middle of the stream, there are two important announcements.
まず1つ目はこちら。
First, here is one.
獅白ぼたん2周年記念グッズ、発売です！イェーイ！
Shishiro Botan's 2nd anniversary commemorative goods are on sale! Yay!
じゃあね、ちょっと簡単にですけど、1つずつ紹介していきます。
So, I'll briefly introduce them one by one.
まず1つ目はこちら、バスタオルです。
First is this, a bath towel.
東西先生のかっこいいデザインが光るバスタオル。
A bath towel with a cool design by Touzai-sensei.
こちらね、もう拭いて良し、飾って良し。
This one, you can use it to wipe yourself or display it.
バスタオルだから、なんだろう、汚れたら洗えるし。
Since it's a bath towel, well, you can wash it if it gets dirty.
あとまぁデザインもかっこいいから、なんかね、体拭くだけじゃなくてさ。
And the design is cool too, so it's not just for drying yourself.
お部屋に飾るとかさ、暖簾にするとかさ。
You can display it in your room, or use it as a curtain.
布団に引いてみるとか。
Or lay it on your futon.
いろいろな活用方法があると思うので、ぜひ良かったら愛用してください。
There are many ways to use it, so please use it as you like.
これね、かっこいいよね。
This is cool, isn't it?
で、続いてはステッカーです。
Next is a sticker.
こちらもね、えっと、サイズが297x200mmくらい。
This one too, the size is about 297x200mm.
なんか13インチのノートパソコンの大きさにペタッと貼れるサイズのステッカーとなってます。
It's a sticker that fits perfectly on a 13-inch laptop.
なので、まぁノートパソコン以外にもね、全然冷蔵庫とか。
So, besides laptops, you can put it on your fridge or something.
箪笥とか、小学生かって感じだけど。
A chest of drawers, though that sounds like a grade-schooler.
いろいろな場所に貼って、もう獅白のかっこよさをぜひアピールしてください。
Paste it in various places and show off Shishiro's coolness.
こちらもね、愛用していただけると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you used this one too.
そして、続いてこちら。
And next is this.
misisa先生描き下ろしの、SSRBランダムラバーキーホルダー。
SSRB random rubber keychains newly drawn by misisa-sensei.
こちらSSRB生みの親のmisisaニキが愛情込めて描いてくれた...
These were drawn with love by misisa-niki, the creator of SSRB...
できました。こちらは、1つ購入するとランダムで1種類お届けする形となります。
It's ready. If you buy one, you'll receive one random type.
キーホルダーの種類ですが、工事看板SSRB、ショッピングカートSSRB...
Keychain types: Construction Sign SSRB, Shopping Cart SSRB...
...ししろんには無理やりロボット化されたSSRB。
...and an SSRB forcibly robotized for Shishiron.
どういう状況？って感じなんですけど。
What's the context here? I wonder.
そして家系SSRBの4種類となっておりますので、ぜひこちらねコンプリートしてくれたら嬉しいなと思っております。
And the Iekei SSRB. There are four types, so I'd love it if you collected them all.
もうこれは複数買い推奨です。自分で言っちゃいますけど。
I recommend buying multiples, even if I do say so myself.
で、最後はこちら、SSRBソックス。
And finally, here are the SSRB socks.
シンプルで使いやすいデザインの靴下となっております。
These socks have a simple and practical design.
ワンポイントでね、SSRBの刺繍とSSRBの書き下ろしロゴが付いてます。このふにゃっとした可愛いロゴがあるのね。
They have SSRB embroidery and a newly drawn logo. This cute, floppy logo.
これ履いて、まあ仕事だったり学校だったり遊びだったり、色んな場所にね、SSRBを連れて行ってくれると嬉しいです。
Wear them and take SSRB with you to work, school, or out for fun!
そして、今回周年記念グッズのフルセットを購入していただいた方には...
And for those who purchase the full set of anniversary goods...
箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りトマリ先生書き下ろしのポストカードが付いてきます。
A postcard by Tomari-sensei with a foil-stamped signature and message is included.
こちらね、表情もちょっと違っているので、ぜひねフルセット購入していただけたら嬉しいなと思っております。よろしくお願いします。
Her expression is different here, so I'd be happy if you bought the full set. Thank you!
そして、重大告知2つ目。お、今回は2つあるのかって感じなんですけど。2つ目、こちら！
Now for the second major announcement. Two this time! Here it is!
なんとなんと新曲が出ます！
Believe it or not, I'm releasing a new song!
ここで発表です。ということで、曲名はですね、「III Love You」。
Announcing it now! The title is "III Love You."
いい曲名だと思うんだよな、私は。こちら、8月14日の24時、つまりね、今日の0時ですね、各音楽配信サイトで聴けるようになります。
I think it's a great title. It'll be on streaming sites from Aug 14th at 24:00—0:00 today!
このさっき言ったね、曲名「III Love You」のね、タイトルをちょっと口ずさみたくなるような歌かもと個人的には思ってるんですが...
Personally, I think it's a song where you'll want to hum the title, "III Love You."
いや、どうでしょうかね？ちょっとその辺はね、聴いてみてください。
Well, what do you think? Please give it a listen.
でね、良かったらぜひTwitterで感想聞かせていただけると嬉しいです。
And please share your thoughts on Twitter if you like it!
以上、重大告知2つでした！ありがとうございました。
That's all for the two major announcements! Thank you!
ということで、オリ曲に、グッズに、いっぱい出るんで、皆さんよかったらぜひグッズは買ってください。オリ曲は聴いてください。よろしくお願いします。
So, with the song and goods coming out, please buy the goods and listen to the song. Thank you!
えーいよいよですね、次の曲が最後となりますので...
Well, the next song will be the last one...
いっぱい練習してきたので、いっぱい見て聴いてくれたら嬉しいなと思います。
I've practiced a lot, so I hope you'll enjoy it to the fullest.
よし、いくぞ。最後の曲だ。
Alright, here we go. The final song.
I pray to stop my cry -little sea style-
白いページ埋めてゆく 悲しい記憶たち",
Sad memories fill the white pages...
見えないように目を伏せるの
...I cast my eyes down so I don't see them.
届かないね小さな叫びは 闇に消され
My small cry doesn't reach, erased by the dark...
耐えられない孤独襲う
...as unbearable loneliness attacks me.
優しい笑顔見せないで これ以上
Don't show me that kind smile anymore...
加速してゆく愛しさが 止まらないから
...because this accelerating love won't stop.
I just pray to stop my tears 涙の後には
I just pray to stop my tears. After the tears...
消せない想いが乾いた光放つ
...feelings that can't be erased emit a dry light...
あなたのそばで
...by your side.
...生きてゆけるなら
...if I can go on living
どんな悲しみも 乗り越えてゆけるのに
Even though I can overcome any sadness
抱えている願いの重さに 追いつけない
I can't catch up to the weight of the wishes I carry
もどかしさが 胸を潰す
This frustration crushes my chest
痛いくらい あなたへの想い 膨らんでく
My feelings for you swell to the point of pain
避けられない 寂しい夜
Lonely nights I can't avoid
叶うのならば もう一度抱きしめて
If it could come true, hold me once more
あなたが触れた 温もりが離れないから
Because the warmth of your touch won't leave me
I just pray to stop my cries 涙の答えは
I just pray to stop my cries, the answer to the tears is
明日を占う 闇に問い掛けてみる
I'll try asking the darkness that predicts tomorrow
苦しいくらい 真っ直ぐな思い
Feelings so straightforward it hurts
伝えられるような 強い勇気が欲しい
I want the strong courage to be able to convey them
I just pray to stop my cries 涙の粒には
I just pray to stop my cries, in the droplets of tears
あなたへと向かう 想いが揺らめいてる
My feelings towards you are flickering
許されるなら 見つめ続けたい
If it's permitted, I want to keep gazing at you
いつかこの胸が 壊れてしまう日まで
Until the day this heart breaks
3年目も一緒に楽しんでいこうね
Let's continue to have fun together in our 3rd year
3年目も一緒に楽しもうね。
Let's have fun together in our third year!
お疲れ様でしたー！
Good work, everyone!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
また遊びに来てね！
Come visit again soon!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!